Zoe Xanos

Chicago, Illinois 60638 | 708-658-8399 | zxanos@gmail.com | Github | Medium Blog | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I strive to bridge the worlds of art and technology. I love pushing the envelope to see what new possibilities are available and what I can create with code. I grew up building machines for science fair projects, painting in my mother's classroom, and obsessively watching A Beautiful Mind in grade school. I want to make the final jump into the tech world and never look back. Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in art. Possess strong skills in communication and creativity that help businesses attract and keep customers. Ready to build innovative projects to increase revenue.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript, React, Python, Figma program, SVG files, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Double Cryptography - https://youtu.be/-9TG-lpDn6c

Created a browser based game using Ruby on Rails for the backend and React for the frontend. Users log in to solve interactive puzzles with the help of a detective.

- Built JSON backend to save user and game data for clean access
- Learned react-konva and implemented an interactive canvas with React
- Constructed svg files for the login page in order to animate text
- Streamlined design for sidebar and main page for easy navigation

Knight Quest - https://github.com/ZXanos/Knight-Quest (add video)

Paired project CLI game created using Ruby on Rails and SQL. Users can choose a knight to journey with or create a new one. Users encounter classic Quest game situations and must find solutions with their knight.

- Communicated with partner to ensure functionality and a successful launch
- Understood user interaction and implemented safety measures to avoid bugs or broken code
- Designed Rails backend where users can save and retrieve knight data
- Generated multiple lines of character dialogue and trials for the user to experience

EXPERIENCE

StarbucksChicago, IllinoisBarista02/2020 - Present

- Increase productivity and team morale by using clear communication completing 50 orders accurately during rush hour
- Assess errors with orders and quickly offer alternatives to ensure happy customers
- Upsell new products and discuss details in menu changes to convey product to customers
- Conduct nightly inventory review of front of the house and prepare items from back of the house to stock for the next shift

Mack & Associates LLC

Chicago, Illinois 12/2018 - 11/2019

Data Analyst/Office Administrator

- Distributed mail and phone calls to staff of two hundred to keep the front desk running smoothly
- Reviewed errors in paperwork for construction company to ensure
- Entered 20-30 entries of data points daily into the officewide database to facilitate accurate voter information

Little Beans Cafe

Chicago, Illinois

Barista/Playspace Attendant

11/2017 - 11/2018

- Assessed needs in decorating, gathering children and parents, and cutting the cake for a seamless party experience
- Maintained clean workspace for safety of children and to help coworkers meet closing deadline

EDUCATION

Harold Washington City College

Chicago, Illinois

Associate of Science in Computer Science

08/2017 - Present

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Javascript, React

Chicago, Illinois

10/2020